# Allan Viguilla

Phone: 908-930-5005

Email: allanviguilla@gmail.com

**Location:** Las Vegas, NV (Open to remote)

#### **SUMMARY**

As a front-end web developer with more than 5 years of experience, I have honed my skills in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I also have full stack experience working on code bases with both SQL and NoSQL databases. Along with my technical skills, I have demonstrated the ability to communicate effectively with technical and non-technical stakeholders.

#### **PROJECTS**

Libre, Social Media application for sharing free time with friends: <a href="https://github.com/allanviguilla/libre">https://github.com/allanviguilla/libre</a>

- Worked with team of engineers and acquired user specs and requirements from client
- Developed clean, efficient, and maintainable code using React and Firebase for Event forms
- Lead the UI design for the application and develop components using Chakra UI

Fresh Threads, Backend microservice for Ecommerce website: https://github.com/allanviguilla/Fresh-Threadz-QA

- Worked with team of engineers to build a performant API for Ecommerce product data
- Developed clean, efficient, and maintainable code in Node.js for Q&A microservice
- Created reports, extracted product data, transformed, and migrated that data to new Postgres database

# **EXPERIENCE**

Shopify Web Developer | Pure Essence Labs,

6 mo. (2021 - 2022)

- Tracked customer conversion rate from product page to checkout using G4 Analytics and Google Tag Manager
- Launched new Subscription and CRM software (Recharge) to increase online store subscriptions by 12%
- Designed and developed new product pages, landing pages, and mobile versions of the website

Junior Web Developer | Arsenal Inc.,

3 yr. 4 mo. (2018 - 2021)

- Created HTML email template to replace image-based emails resulting in a 3% increase in open rate
- Designed and developed product pages and landing pages for new product releases and marketing events
- Manage ecommerce site data including extracting, merging, and restructuring product and customer information

Student Web Developer | Civic Engagement Computer Center @ NJIT,

**2** yr. **7** mo. (2015 - 2017)

- Worked with community organizations to gather user specifications and requirements for website projects
- Designed and developed code, reports, and related data analysis for website builds
- Provided technical support and created documentation on how to update, maintain, and use their websites

#### **EDUCATION**

New Jersey Institute of Technology | Bachelor's of Science, Web and Information Systems,

→ Studied Web Development, User Experience Research and Design, and Computer Programming concepts.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front End | JavaScript, React, React Native, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Chakra UI, MUI Full Stack | Node.js, Next.js, Python, ASP.NET, C#, Java, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, Axios, RESTful APIs Testing & Deployment | Jest, Mocha, Chai, AWS: EC2 / RDS / S3, Expo Dev Tools | Vim, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Agile Methodology, Scrum, TDD

# **CERTIFICATES**

Advanced Software Engineering Certificate from *Hack Reactor* 

12-week software engineering immersive program with over 1000+ hours of pair programming, team
programming, and solo work. Full-Stack development with JavaScript, React, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,
and MySQL in an AGILE environment.